不
No.
不不
No, no!
今晚想做点什么吗
You want to do something tonight?
当然  如果你想的话
Sure. If you want.
好啊
Sure.
做什么
Like what?
我们可以  看个电影
We could, um, go watch a movie.
好啊  如果你想的话
Yeah. Yeah, if you want to.
你不想就算了
Well, not if you don't want to.
-如果你想我就想  -那个
- No, if you want to, I-I want to. - You know what?
-我们这几周看过好几场电影了  -是啊
- We've watched a lot of movies over the past couple weeks. - Yeah.
那或许我们可以...
So, maybe we could,
如果你想的话
you know, if you wanted...
我想什么
If I wanted to what?
今晚可以做点别的
I mean, we could try something else tonight.
别的什么
Something else as in...
嗯...我们还没...
Yeah, I mean, we haven't since...
是啊  因为发生了那么多事
Yeah, well, given everything that's happened,
我以为你是没...准备好呢
I thought you just... you weren't...Ready.
我以为是你没准备好
I thought that you weren't ready.
我准备好好的了
I'm ready.
我...
I'm... I
绝对准备好了
I'm... I'm so ready.
我也准备好了  我真的准备好了
I-I'm ready, too. Like, I'm really ready.
好吧  那我们在等什么啊
Okay. Well, then what are we waiting for?
怎么了
What?
你保证
You promise?
当然  待会儿继续
Yes, we'll pick up where we left off.
我还会穿你的情人节礼物
I'll even slip into that valentine's day gift you got me.
就是那件...
You mean the one with...
-那个...  -没错
- With... - Yeah.
穿过他胸膛的那是台球杆吗
Is that a pool cue through his chest?
看来不用问死因了
Guess we don't have to ask how he died.
下腔静脉被刺穿
Inferior vena cava was punctured.
他数分钟内流血致死
He bled out in minutes.
死亡时间呢
And when did that happen?
楼下的夫妇
The couple in the unit downstairs
7点50听到了打斗声便报了警
heard a struggle at 7:50 and called 911.
他们说听上去打得很厉害
They said it sounded like a hell of a fight.
被害人名叫威廉·法维克  25岁
Victim's name is William Fairwick. He was 25.
还有什么别的信息吗
What else do we know about him?
除了知道他喜欢无政府主义纹身
Other than his taste in anarchy tattoos
和撒旦图样  其他还不清楚
and satanic design, not much yet.
他的笔记本和手机都有密码
His laptop and phone were both password protected.
抱歉  地铁好堵
So sorry. Subway took forever.
哥们  你是待命人员
Bro, you're supposed to be on call.
你怎么一身酒气
Why do you smell like a wino?
我跟珍妮吃晚饭了
Oh, I was at dinner with Jenny,
我跑出餐馆的时候被人洒上了酒
and someone spilled a drink on me as I rushed out.
嗯
Yeah.
这一道碎片是从左及右的
The debris from this breakage goes from left to right.
那么行凶的是左撇子
So, whoever did it was left handed.
而且应该是受邀入门
Most likely invited.
门窗都从里面锁好了
All the doors and windows were locked from the inside,
虽然打得一团乱  但没有强行闯入的迹象
And despite the wreckage, there's no sign of forced entry.
有什么被盗吗
Was anything stolen?
没什么明显的贵重物品被盗
None of the obvious valuables,
但我在他的袜子抽屉最里面发现了这个
but I did find this stashed in the back of his sock drawer.
是两万块现金
It's $20,000 in cash.
凶手可能就是在找这个
Could be what the killer was looking for.
留在家里挺冒险啊
That's pretty risky leaving it here.
这家伙是做什么的
What did this guy do for a living?
看啊  我找到了他的工作证
Hey, check it out. I found his work I.D.
上面写着格林布拉特保险公司
It says here "Greenblatt Insurance."
我去查查  看看有没有关联
I'll track it down, see if it has any relevance.
天呐  威尔
Oh, my god, Will?!
怎么回事
What happened?
嗯  我们做了两年邻居了
Yeah, we've been neighbors for two years.
我们下班后有时一起玩游戏
We played video games after work sometimes.
我就是来看他在不在
I was just seeing if he was around.
你整晚都在吗  亨利
Were you here all night, Henry?
是的
Yeah.
那你听到什么声音了吗
So, did you hear anything?
抱歉  我一整晚都在围攻柯巴尔德城堡
Sorry, I've been laying siege to the fortress of Kobald all night.
大地远征里的吗
From "Terra Quest"?
你是什么  狡猾的西部食尸鬼
What are you... a wily westland ghoul?
凶狠的南方河怪
Menacing south river orc?
东山妖精
East mountain goblin.
其实  我是国王
I'm, uh, their king, actually.
厉害啊
Respect.
总之  回到现实世界中
Anyway, back to the real world.
威尔最近有什么奇怪之处吗
So, did Will exhibit any odd behavior recently?
没有  跟往常一样啊
No. It was pretty much the same routine.
早上去上班  晚上回来
I mean, he'd go to work in the morning, come home at night.
好吧  他提到过其他的朋友吗
Okay. Did he talk about any of his other friends?
谁最近跟他有矛盾
Was he having troubles with anyone?
我们不怎么谈现实生活的事
We didn't talk much about real-life stuff.
主要就是交流游戏
It was mainly just "Terra Quest."
但如果他遇到了麻烦
But if he was having a problem,
大概跟他赚钱的生意有关
it probably had something to do with how he made his money.
在格林布拉特保险公司吗
At Greenblatt Insurance?
理赔人只是他的日间工作
Claims adjuster, that... that was just his day job.
他每晚在切尔西台球厅能挣很多钱
He was making a fortune every night over at Chelsea Billiards.
他是个台球赌棍
Guy was a pool hustler.
这就解释了袜子抽屉里的现金
That explains the cold, hard cash we found in his sock drawer.
还有穿过他胸膛的台球杆
And the pool cue we found in his chest.
嗯  威尔是在我这边工作
Yeah. Will worked my tables.
他是我见过的最厉害的
He was the best I ever seen.
什么角度都会打
Knew all the angles.
被他赢钱的人有谁对他有不满吗
Anyone he took for money ever have a problem with him?
当然  但我们主要拿华尔街的二货开刀
Sure, but will mostly hustled Wall Street tools
一场也就一千
for 10 bills a game.
输个一两千  对他们来说不算什么
Losing a grand here or there is chump change for them.
那些人是不会为了一场赌博杀人的
None of those guys would ever kill will over a bet.
但有人会吗
But there are guys that would?
威尔一直在我这种高档俱乐部干活儿
Will always worked - the upscale clubs like mine
拿客人的钱是很安全的
where it's safe to take money off the clientele.
但最近  我听说他开始在布鲁克林的
But recently, I'd heard that he started hustling
奥尼尔酒吧赌博
out in Brooklyn at O'neill's.
那里净是重罪犯和人渣
That place is full of felons and lowlifes.
知道他为什么跑去了那儿吗
Any idea why he decided to move his game up there?
肯定不是为了钱  他在这儿赚的很多
Well, it wasn't for the money. I mean, he was cleaning up here.
但是
But, uh...
但是人说话  做事
What people say and do...
并不总合乎逻辑的
doesn't always make sense.
谢泼德先生
Mr. Shepherd?
也许只是我多心了
No, it's probably nothing.
说来挺傻的
It's stupid, even.
要是能帮我们
It's not stupid if it could help us
了解威尔的情况就不傻
fill in the blanks on Will's life.
我曾问过他  他怎么这么厉害
I once asked him - how he got to be so good.
他跟我说他去了十字路口
He told me he went down to the crossroads,
跟魔鬼做了交易  换来天赋
made a deal with the devil for his talent.
我觉得  他只是在开玩笑对吧
I figured that's -- that -- that's got to be a joke, right?
但有天晚上  他看起来很紧张
But the other night, he looked nervous.
很明显在害怕
I mean, downright scared,
所以我问他说  你怎么啦
so I asked him, I said, "What's going on?"
你知道他说什么吗
You know what he told me?
不  但我绝对想知道
No, but I want to know.
他说他那天没在开玩笑
He said it wasn't a joke.
他说他大限已到
He said his time was up --
他要失去他的灵魂了
that he was about to lose his soul.
我说了的  很傻对吧
Well, like I said, though, uh, stupid, right?
埃斯波有线索  在分局等我们呢
Espo's got something for us at the precinct.
一个人说他要失去灵魂了紧接着就应验了
A guy says he's gonna lose his soul and then he does?
难道不诡异吗
How creepy is that?
是那人惹上了恶棍招致了死亡
The guy was hustling felons and he got himself killed.
这不是诡异  不过恐怕是死因
That's not creepy, that's probable cause.
被害人的雇主查到什么了吗
Anything on our vic's employer?
是的
Uh, yeah.
我查到格林布拉特公司一个1-800打头的电话号
I got a 1-800 number for greenblatt insurance,
但他们明天才营业呢
but they're closed until tomorrow.
你回家时能顺路去一趟
Can you stop by O'Neill's bar
布鲁克林的奥尼尔酒吧吗
in Brooklyn on your way home,
查访一下是否有人见过被害人
ask around about the vic?
要是珍妮在等你就算了
Unless Jenny needs you?
没  可以的
No, all good.
埃斯波  查到什么了
Espo, what do we got?
我拿到了威尔公寓的监控录像
I pulled security footage from Will's building.
电梯旁有个摄像头
There's a security camera in the elevator area
刚好能看到威尔的房间
slightly angled - towards Will's apartment.
我设法放大了录像
I was able to magnify the footage.
很好  那我们就能看到
Great, then we should be able to pull an image
凶手离开他房间的过程了
of our killer leaving the apartment.
按理说没错  但是  你自己看吧
We should, yeah, but... Watch.
这是报警电话前一分钟的录像
This is a minute before the 911 call.
这是报警一分钟后的
And this is minutes later.
门自己开了又关上
The door opens and closes on its own,
之后到警察到达前
and then no one enters
没有一个人进出过那个房间
or exits the apartment until police arrive,
所有的窗户  都是从里面锁上的
and all the windows were locked from the inside.
这不可能
That's impossible.
凶手肯定用某种方法进出过房间
The killer had to get in and out somehow.
能再放一遍吗
Uh, can you play that again?
凶手就在那儿
There's your killer right there.
还不明白吗
Don't you see?
威尔和魔鬼做了交易
Will made a deal with the devil.
合同到期了  付出代价的时候到了
The contract was up, so it was time to pay.
魔鬼如期而至  完成了交易
The devil came and got his due.
是吗
Really?
魔鬼就是这么杀人的吗
That's how the devil is gonna kill someone --
用一根折断的台球杆
using a broken pool stick?
也许是黑暗王子想要
Well, perhaps the prince of darkness
以此传达一个讯息
is trying to make a point.
你以此为生  也就因此而死
You live by the cue, you die by the cue.
我以为他一般都直接让地狱猎犬动手呢
Thought he usually just released the hell hounds.
好吧  那你怎么解释
All right, then how do you explain
我们看到的录像
what we just saw back there?
简单
Easy.
威尔跑进屋时并没有关门
Will didn't close the door all the way when he came back in.
窗户开着
Our window was open.
凶手从窗户进来
The killer came through,
一股狂风进来吹开了门
and this huge gust of wind forced the door open
风停后门就关上了
and then shut when they left.
但埃斯波西托说了
But Esposito said
所有窗户都是从里面锁上的
all the windows were locked from the inside.
凶手是职业杀手
Our killer's a pro.
他知道怎么从外面锁上窗户
He knows how to reset interior locks.
但威尔住19层  大楼还没逃生梯
Except Will lives on the 19th floor with no fire escape.
拜托  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
你知道要想进没有逃生梯的高层的窗户
You know that there are plenty of ways to access windows
也是有很多办法的
on high-level floors without a fire escape.
没错  对蜘蛛侠来说的话
Yes. If you're spider-man.
凶手不是蜘蛛侠
Our killer's not spider-man.
同意  因为凶手是魔鬼
Agreed... Because it's the devil.
此案中只有一个地方能找到魔鬼
The only place - that we're gonna find the devil
因为关键[魔鬼]藏在细节里
in this case is in the details.
只要对威尔的生活有了更详尽的了解
Once we find out more about Will's life,
我们就能揭开  他人类敌人的神秘面纱
then we will uncover - who his earthbound enemy is.
明天再揭
Tomorrow.
今晚  我想回家去玩
Tonight, I have something I'd like to uncover
脱衣游戏
back at home.
不要接
Don't answer that.
不要  看都不要看
Don't. Don't even. Don't look at it.
-别接  -我只是
- Don't answer it. - I just want --
不要接
Don't pick it up.
你接了
You picked it up.
-是蕾妮啊  -蕾妮
- Oh, Lanie. Yes. - Lanie!
好  我马上过去
Okay. I'll be right there.
进一步检查过尸体后
On closer examination of the body,
我在被害人的左手手腕处
I found multiple stress fractures here
发现了多处撕裂
on the victim's left wrist.
怎么弄的
From what?
撕裂伤有屈曲性损伤  拉伤
Well, they're consistent with flexion, extension,
过伸性损伤
and hyperextension,
就像一个左撇子
as a left-handed person would experience if --
拿着台球杆  破坏周围的一切时弄的
They grabbed a pool cue - and smashed everything to bits.
说明威尔是左撇子
So, Will's left handed.
你是说毁掉他公寓的人是他自己吗
Are you saying that will destroyed his own apartment?
盲目地挥舞台球杆来保护自己
Swinging a pool cue blindly to defend himself?
我告诉你  这完全合理
Telling you, it makes perfect sense.
要是你在被隐形的恶魔攻击
What would you do if you were attacked
你会怎么办
by an invisible demonic force?
我会让莱恩中午别吃加豆墨西哥卷了
I'd tell Ryan to lay off the bean burritos at lunch.
两位
Hey, guys.
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
你是对的
So, you were right.
威尔的麻烦  可能真的是在
Will's troubles may have followed him home
奥尼尔台球厅惹上的
from O'Neill's pool hall.
我询问了多个目击者
I spoke with several witnesses who said
他上星期在那里跟一个叫吉格·麦克斯的
that he got into an altercation there last week
释放犯发生过争执
with an ex-con named Jiggy Michaels.
争执有多严重
How serious was the altercation?
吉格砸碎了一个啤酒瓶  威胁要杀了他
Well, Jiggy smashed a beer bottle, threatened to kill him.
好几个人不得不拦住他
Several people had to hold him back.
这算得上严重了
That qualifies as serious.
威尔赢了他两万块钱
Apparently, Will hustled him out of 20 grand.
我们在他家就发现了这么多钱
That's the exact same amount of money we found at his apartment.
而且  吉格有很多前科  包括多次强行闯入
Plus, Jiggy has over a dozen priors, including multiple B&Es.
他能毫无声息地出入别人家
He can get in and out undetected.
大家管他叫"幽灵"
They call him the Ghost.
一个真实存在的杀手能够毫无声息地出入
A real-world killer who can get in and out undetected.
这才是个完美的解释
Now, that makes perfect sense.
我要律师
I want a lawyer.
我不是第一次进来了
This ain't my first rodeo.
很不幸
Well, that is too bad,
因为律师会让你什么都不要说
because a lawyer is gonna tell you not to talk.
可这样的话  你怎么跟大陪审团解释
And how are you gonna explain to a grand jury
那个你威胁过的  曾经赢了你钱的人
that you threatened to kill a guy who hustled you,
三天后  竟然被杀死了
and then, three days later, he ended up dead?
作为多个犯罪组织的窃贼
As a second-story man for several crime outfits,
你知道怎么闯入法维克的家
you knew how to break into Fairwick's place,
但是当你找不到钱时
but when you couldn't find your money,
就决心要报复了
you settled on revenge instead.
我们找到了一张出租车小票
We've got a taxi receipt
显示你昨晚去了切尔西
dropping you off at Chelsea last night,
离威尔的家只有三个街区
three blocks from Will's apartment.
那里距你在赛普里斯山的家相当得远  吉格
That's a long way from your place in Cypress Hills, Jiggy.
我的男朋友住在切尔西
My boyfriend lives in Chelsea.
我一整晚都跟他在一起
I was with him all night.
还有  威尔不是赢了我的钱  他作弊了
And Will didn't hustle me. He cheated me.
打到一半时  那混蛋跟我赌翻倍  赢家全拿
Half a game in, that cujo bet me double or nothing
然后一杆就全清了台上的球
and cleared the rest of the table with a single shot.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
那个母球就像着了魔了
It was like that cue ball was possessed or something.
没人能那么厉害  或者那么幸运
No one is that good or that lucky,
所以是的  我很生气  但我没有杀他
So, yeah, I got pissed, but I didn't kill the guy.
事实上  威尔第二天找到了我
In fact, Will tracked me down the next day
并提出要把钱还给我
and offered to give the money back.
是吗
Really?
他真的打算把两万块钱还给你
He was just gonna pay you back $20,000,
怎么  他突然良心发现
What, out of the kindness of his heart?
是用来换取消息的
In exchange for some knowledge.
这消息可够贵的  你为他做了什么
That's some expensive knowledge. What did you do for him?
什么也没做  我们只是聊了聊
I didn't do anything. We just talked.
那威尔想知道什么
So, what did Will want to know?
他想让我去踩点上东区一户有钱人家
He wanted me to case a brownstone on the Upper East Side.
这不光是聊聊这么简单
That sounds like more than talking.
我已经不干那一行了
I don't do that stuff anymore.
威尔只是想问问他怎么能进去
Will just asked how he could break in himself.
为什么  那户人家有什么特别的
Why? What was so special about that brownstone?
我不知道  但想进去绝非易事
I don't know, but it wasn't gonna be easy.
那户人家也有准备
I mean, place had the works --
运动检测器  压力和热量传感器
motion detectors, pressure and thermal sensors.
想要进去简直就是疯了
You'd have to be nuts to try to go in there.
你看这样好不好  我们当没听见
What do you say that we forget
你给他传授闯入人家的"秘籍"
that you were acting like the Wikipedia of B&Es?
但你要把那户人家的地址告诉我们
And you give us the address of that brownstone.
在这周早些时候  七十大街东39号
There was a break-in at 39 East 70th Street
确实发生过一起入室盗窃
earlier this week,
户主汤姆·塔尔梅奇受到了袭击
and the owner, Tom Talmadge, was assaulted.
汤姆·塔尔梅奇
Tom Talmadge?
他是这个拼车服务Hytch的创始人
He's the founder of that ride-share service, Hytch.
车顶上有大拇指的那种车
The stupid cars with the thumbs on the roof?
随你怎么嘲笑  这个应用让他成了亿万富翁
Laugh all you want. That app made him a billionaire.
威尔闯入亿万富翁的家干什么
What's Will doing breaking into a billionaire's house?
不知道  但有件事很奇怪
I don't know, but here's the weird thing.
汤姆进了医院  但他拒绝
Tom was hospitalized and he refused
告诉警察袭击者的容貌
to give a description of the attacker.
这和威尔几天后被杀绝不是巧合
Can't be a coincidence that Will shows up dead a few days later.
不是  他在隐瞒什么
No. He's hiding something.
我已经跟别的警察说了
I already told the other cops --
我不想录口供
I don't want to give a statement.
塔尔梅奇先生
Mr. Talmadge,
你跟威廉·法维克是什么关系
What's your relationship to William Fairwick?
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who that is.
塔尔梅奇先生  你的反应出卖了你
Mr. Talmadge, your reaction says otherwise.
是他袭击的你吗
Was he your attacker?
我不要录口供
I'm not giving a statement.
鉴于法维克先生被杀了
Given that Mr. Fairwick was murdered,
你最好还是再考虑一下
you might want to rethink that.
被杀了
Murdered?
如果你们是觉得我跟这件事有什么关系
Look, if you're implying that I had something to do with it --
那你为什么拒绝回答问题
Well, why else would you refuse to answer the question?
因为你们肯定不会相信我
Because you won't believe me anyway.
听起来太离谱了
It'll sound crazy.
离谱的事我们见得多了
You wouldn't believe the crazy things we've heard.
说说吧
Try us.
那天我早回家了  开了瓶啤酒
I'd gotten home early, cracked a beer,
但是在我坐下前
but before I could settle in,
我有种感觉  像是有人在盯着我
I had this feeling like I was being watched.
然后  突然之间
Then out of nowhere,
有东西把我砸倒在地
something threw me to the ground.
等一下  有东西
Wait. Some thing?
你是说他吧
You mean him, right?
不  我是指某个东西
No. I mean some thing.
某种力量
Some force.
我能感觉到它压在我身上  让我窒息
I could feel it on top of me, suffocating me,
但是  但是又什么也没有
But -- but there was nothing there.
我一定是晕过去了一段时间
I must've blacked out for a second,
等我醒来时
And when I came to,
那个人站在我面前  喊着"住手
that guy was standing over me, screaming, "Stop it.
你要弄死他了  我们的计划不是这样的"
You're killing him. This wasn't the deal."
-他在跟谁喊  -我不知道
- And who was he yelling at? - I don't know.
那里没有别人了
There wasn't anybody else there.
但我觉得这个人  他救了我一命
But I think that guy, he saved my life.
这个所谓的力量  它想要什么
This force, what did it want?
似乎  它是想要我
It just seemed like it wanted... me.
好吧
Okay. Fine.
我承认这很诡异
I admit it is weird.
但我敢肯定
But I can tell you this.
无论塔尔梅奇看到或没看到的是什么
Whatever Talmadge saw or didn't see,
那绝不是魔鬼
it wasn't the devil.
你说得对  可能是它的一个小鬼
You're right. Probably one of his minions.
魔鬼派这个低级小鬼
A lowly demon that will summoned from beelzebub
去帮它从塔尔梅奇那里弄到它想要的东西
to help him get whatever it was he wanted from Talmadge.
魔鬼是不需要帮助就能通过安保系统的
Demons don't need help - getting past security systems,
也用不着走门
and the devil doesn't need to use the door.
我会再看一遍威尔公寓的
I'm gonna take another look at that security-cam footage
监控录像
from Will's apartment.
那光碟哪去了
Where's the DVD?
什么光碟
What DVD?
我把监控录像的光碟放在这个证据箱里了
I put a DVD of security footage in this evidence box.
哪去了
Where is it?
不在的话  就是你没放进来
Ain't in there, you didn't put it in there.
我没放进来才怪
The hell I didn't.
前两个小时谁来过
Who's been in here the past two hours?
探长  从你今天早上查看这个箱子之后
Detective, no one's been in or out of this room
就没有人进出过这里
since you checked that box in this morning.
那光碟怎么没了呢
So, what did it do?
自己走出去了吗
Just walk out on its own?
不是
No.
它不是自己走出去的
It didn't walk out on its own.
贝克特  你说得对
Beckett, you were right.
凶手不是什么恶魔
Killer isn't the devil.
恶魔用不着销毁证据
The devil doesn't need to dispose of evidence.
很明显
Clearly.
明显这个词用得真是恰当
"Clearly" is the perfect word,
因为很明显  我们要找的凶手是隐形人
Because clearly, our killer is the invisible man.
你毁了咖啡的奶泡
You collapsed the foam.
我给威尔的公寓打电话
So, I called Will's place
想再把监控的录像调出来
to pull security-cam footage from the hallway again,
可是所有的文件都被清除了
and all the files have been erased.
门卫确定纽约警局离开犯罪现场后
The doorman swears that no one has been in the security room
没有人到过安保室
since NYPD left the crime scene.
没有人  还是有某个他看不到的人
No one - or someone he couldn't see?
贝克特  这个推论符合全部事实
Beckett, it fits all the facts.
塔尔梅奇被一股无形的力量袭击
The attack on Talmadge by an unseen force,
丢失的证据
the missing evidence,
诡异的白色撞球  甚至威尔的凶杀案
the haunted cue ball, even Will's murder.
卡塞尔  打住
Castle, stop.
这个世上没有什么隐形人
There is no such thing as the invisible man.
但肯定有蹊跷  而威尔是其中的关键
But something is going on, and Will is at the center of it.
埃斯波
Hey, Espo.
威尔·法维克身上还有什么发现
What else have we found on Will Fairwick?
莱恩还在联系
Well, Ryan's still trying to get in touch
他的公司  格林布拉特保险公司
with his employer, Greenblatt Insurance,
托瑞正在里面破解他的电子设备
and Tory's in there trying to crack his electronics.
显然威尔在硬件的加密很厉害
Apparently, Will had some heavy encryption on his hardware.
对于一个在保险业工作的人来说
That seems a little unnecessary
这么严的加密有点没必要
for someone in the insurance industry.
我刚从他的无线运营商那
Yeah, but I just got his phone records
拿到了他的电话记录
from his wireless carrier,
这家伙不怎么打电话
And dude didn't talk much
除了这里的这个号码
except to this one number right here.
过去的六周里他给这号码打了几十通电话
He traded dozens of calls with it over the past six weeks,
在此之前他从没有联系过这个号码
and he didn't ever call it before then.
看上去他们几乎每天都要通话
Looks like they spoke nearly every day.
这号码是谁的
Who owns that number?
是一位名叫多娜·布鲁克斯的女士注册的
It's registered to a Ms. Donna Brooks.
这显示她是哈德逊大学的海洋生物学教授
Says here that she's a marine biology professor at Hudson U.
他在做什么  要和生物教授联系
What's he doing - talking to a biology professor?
我好几天都没有他的消息了
I hadn't heard from him in a few days.
我很担心  但我没想过事情会是这样
I was worried, but I never imagined this.
我不敢相信他已经死了
I can't believe he's dead.
多娜我知道很难接受  但你怎么认识威尔的
Donna, I know this is hard, but how do you know Will?
我想你可以说我们在约会
Um, I guess you could say we were dating.
他几个月前在脸书上联系我
He reached out on facebook a couple months ago.
自从在麻省理工约过会后我就没见过他
I hadn't seen him since we first dated back at M.I.T.
支持无政府主义的桌球老手上过麻省理工
An anarchist pool shark attended M.I.T.?
他一直都很叛逆
He was always a rebel,
也是我们班上最聪明的学生
and the smartest student in our class.
他为什么要再和你联系
Why did he get back in touch?
威尔只上了一个学期就退学了
Will dropped out after only a semester.
他想找我谈谈完成学位的事情
So he wanted to talk about finishing his degree,
在哈德逊上学
enrolling here at Hudson.
过了这么久
It was crazy after all that time,
我们之间还能擦出火花真是太不可思议了
the spark was still there between us.
不好意思
Excuse me.
墨鱼不喜欢这样
Cuttlefish don't like that.
好吧
Right.
他有没有提过汤姆·塔尔梅奇这个名字
Did he ever mention the name Tom Talmadge?
没有  我印象中没有
Uh, no. Not that I remember.
威尔的生活中
And was there anything out of the ordinary
有没有什么不寻常的地方
going on in Will's life?
比如超出常理很多很多的东西
Like way, way, way out of the ordinary.
有
Yeah. There was.
从上周开始威尔变得有些多疑
Will started acting paranoid last week.
我们去吃饭的时候
We went to dinner,
他只愿意坐在正对门口的位置
and he would only take a table facing the door.
他觉得自己被人监视了
He said he thought he was being watched.
被谁
By who?
他只是说  他们
He would only say by "Them."
我以为这都是他乱想出来的
I thought he was imagining it.
我跟他说他需要帮助
I told him he needed to get help
才不至于让麻省理工的事情再次发生
so it didn't become M.I.T. all over again.
在麻省理工的时候发生了什么
What happened at M.I.T.?
大一的时候  威尔崩溃了
Freshman year, Will had a breakdown.
在很大的压力下他承受不住了
He cracked under the pressure.
所以他才离开了
That's why he left.
但如果他是被杀的
But if somebody killed him,
那有可能他真是被人跟踪了
then maybe he was being followed.
也可以这么想
Okay, here's a theory.
万一是威尔又一次崩溃了呢
What if will had another breakdown?
万一是他臆想出来恶魔要来找他
What if he imagined that the devil was after him,
在他的妄想中自己把公寓毁掉了
and in his delusional state, he smashed up his apartment
然后把自己钉死了呢
and impaled himself?
吃了迷幻药的人做过比这还糟的事
I mean, we've seen guys on pcp do much worse.
但还是不能解释塔尔梅奇遭受的袭击
Well, that still doesn't explain the attack on Talmadge,
奇特一杆清台  还有消失的证据
The magical pool shot, or all the disappearing evidence.
不  事情要比这严重
No, something much bigger is going on here.
你知道吗  我觉得卡塞尔是对的
You know, I think Castle may be right.
我终于联系上了格林布拉特保险公司
I finally got in touch with Greenblatt Insurance.
他们说他是在职员工  但是是远程员工
They say he is on the payroll, but as a remote employee.
格林布拉特唯一的办公室在芝加哥
Greenblatt's only office is in Chicago,
威尔从来都没去过那
and Will's never been there.
但是他的邻居说他看见威尔每天都去工作
But his neighbor said he saw him go into work every day.
而且他的工作出入证
Yep, and his Greenblatt key card
跟钥匙挂在一起  有很多刮痕  都磨旧了
was with his house keys and all scratched up, worn.
如果格林布拉特在纽约没有办事处
So, if Greenblatt doesn't have a New York office,
那威尔每天都去了哪里呢
where was Will going every day?
听上去格林布拉特保险公司是个幌子
Sounds like Greenblatt Insurance is a front.
莱恩  这张门卡现在在哪里
Ryan, where is this key card now?
还在威尔的公寓里
Back at Will's apartment.
你这是在干什么
What are you doing?
我们不知道隐形人现在是不是也在这里
We don't know if the invisible man is here right now.
那个隐形人是不是捏你屁股了
Did the invisible man just goose you?
-卡塞尔  -我知道
- Castle. - I know.
他们就是这样的人  太没礼貌了
They're like that. So gauche.
格林布拉特保险公司
威廉·法维克
好了
Right.
演得真像
That's pretty good.
隐形的部分被你诠释得...
You're really selling the invisible ...
这是  这是真的
This is -- this is real!
我碰到了  不论那是什么  我碰到了
I touched it. Whatever it was, I touched it!
卡塞尔
Castle!
他是来抢门卡的
He's going after the key card!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
刚才到底是什么
What was that?
就是他
That was him.
隐形人真的存在
The invisible man is real!
是的
Yeah.
不论那个  不论那个是什么
Well, whatever it...That -- whatever it was,
他带着我们唯一的线索跑掉了
It just ran off - with the only lead we have.
没有
No.
他带走的是我的信用卡
It ran off with my credit card.
我拼死保住了这张门卡
I managed to hang on to the key card.
你不会觉得他还在这里吧
You don't think - he's still here, do you?
你们在封锁的犯罪现场被袭击了  被谁
You were attacked at a closed crime scene? By whom?
我们没能看清楚袭击者的长相  长官
We didn't get a good look at the assailant, sir.
其实  我们
Actually, we --
怎么了  卡塞尔先生
Yes, Mr. Castle?
当时很黑  我们什么都没看见
It was dark and we didn't see anything.
你们知道为什么那人会在那里吗
Do you know why this person was there?
我们确信他们是想拿到被害者的门卡
We believe they were after the victim's key card.
为什么
Why?
他们是想介入威尔的某部分生活吗
Were they trying to gain access to some part of Will's life?
也许他们是想掩盖罪证
Or maybe they were covering their tracks
不想让我们知道那张卡能打开哪扇门
and don't want us to know what door that card opens.
我已经让鉴证科重新处理犯罪现场了
I've got CSU reprocessing the crime scene.
他们正在寻找新的指纹
They're looking for new prints,
托瑞会把那张门卡和安全系统
and Tory's gonna try to match the key card
进行匹配
to, um, to security systems.
她明早就会开工
She's gonna start that first thing in the morning.
好的  有新消息通知我
All right. Um, keep me posted.
你有什么事情没告诉我吗
Is there something you're not telling me?
没有  长官
No, sir.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
对你的上级撒谎
Lying to your superior?
我说的是事实
I told her the truth.
我不知道是什么袭击了我俩
I don't know what attacked us.
我没说谎
That was not a lie.
忽略是无形的谎言
Omission is the invisible lie.
卡塞尔  别跟我说之前发生的事
Castle, you can't tell me that what happened
没有吓到你  哪怕一点点
didn't freak you out just a little bit.
-那到底是什么  -我不知道
- I mean, what the hell was that thing? - I don't know.
但我知道有个能放松一下的方法
But I do know a way to take our minds off it for a while
如果你
if you're, uh...
有兴趣的话
Interested?
你根本不知道我是有多想念这个
You have no idea how much I missed this.
你失去了两个月的记忆
You had amnesia for two months.
我更想念
I missed it more.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
别吓人了  卡塞尔
Very funny, Castle.
我认真的
I'm serious.
就是音乐声
No, just hear the music.
是你的手在我的腿上吗
Is that your hand on my leg?
是的
Yeah.
-绝对是  -好吧
- Pretty sure. - Okay.
来吧
Okay.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我觉得  我觉得们正在被人看着
I just -- I feel like we're being watched.
我很确定没人在看我们
Pretty sure we're not being watched.
我相信你  不过也许现在不适合干这个
I know, but maybe this isn't such a good idea.
在这儿等我
Just wait here.
好吧
Okay.
你还觉得参加僵尸末日生存训练营
And you thought zombie apocalypse survival camp
是浪费时间呢
was a waste of time.
很好  不错
Good. Okay.
怎么了
What?
你突然有种书呆子式的性感
You just kind of make nerdy sexy.
说的没错
That's true.
刚才到哪儿了
Where were we?
母亲
Mother.
玛莎
Martha?
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我不知道你们在家
I didn't know you guys were home.
我就是想来拿点牙线
I just wanted a little dental floss,
看来我是找到了
And it looks like I found it.
我的天呐
Oh, my lord.
鉴证科重新处理犯罪现场
So, CSU reprocessed that crime scene.
没发现新的指纹  这就说明
No new fingerprints, which means --
拜托  隐形人
Come on. The invisible man?
我就这么说说
I'm just saying,
贝克特昨晚都有点被吓到了
even Beckett seemed freaked out last night.
如果可以隐形  还真挺酷的
It would be cool, the power of invisibility.
我肯定会溜进51区的  你呢
I would so sneak into Area 51. You?
超级碗  50码处
Super bowl, 50-yard line.
全场最佳的座...
Best seat in the hou...
你脖子上的是什么
Hey, what's that on your neck?
那是闪光粉吗
Is that -- is that body glitter?
你被人挠了
Is that a scratch?
没  没什么
No, it's nothing.
结了婚的女人是不擦闪光粉的
Married women don't wear body glitter.
到底怎么了
What's going on?
你对珍妮做了什么不忠的事
You stepping out on Jenny?
等等  什么  没有
Wait. What? N-no.
她可是你孩子的母亲
She's the mother of your kid.
我正是为了我的孩子做的
I am doing this for my kid.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你知不知道把萨拉·格蕾丝送进大学
Do you realize how much it's gonna cost
要花多少钱
to send Sarah Grace to college?
25万美元  还是州立学校
A quarter of a million dollars. That's for a state school.
我就找了份晚班兼职
Well, I'm -- I've got a second job working nights.
做什么
Doing what?
在俱乐部当保安
Bouncing at a club.
用闪光粉的俱乐部
Where they use body glitter?
脱衣舞俱乐部
A gentleman's club.
是"翘臀"还是"管位"
Is it Bottom's Up? Pole Position?
不不不  "着陆地带"
No, no, no. Landing Strip.
-男哈顿  -什么
- Men-hattan. - What?
男哈顿
Men-hattan.
Men-hattan?
你的找份兼职保护脱衣舞男
You got a job protecting male strippers?
天呐
Oh, my god.
不是开玩笑
It's no joke.
那工作比这危险多了
It's more dangerous than this job.
那些女人  疯狂地冲到台上
Those women, they rush the stage
就好像那些男人是地球上仅存的男性
like these are - the last men on the planet.
我身上的擦伤都不知道怎么弄的
I have bruises that I can't explain.
那些女人都疯了  哈维
Ladies be crazy, Javi.
我从未见过类似这卡的无线射频识别构造
The card's RFID architecture is like nothing I've ever seen.
关于这卡
Yeah, but there's got to be something else
没什么别的线索吗
that you can tell us about it.
只能告诉你  这不是为了销售生产的
I can tell you this -- it's not commercially manufactured.
那无政府主义男是怎么拿到它的
Well, how did anarchy boy get it, then?
我不知道  恐怕没办法查出来
I don't know, and I'm afraid there's no way to find out.
这卡片的设计使它无迹可寻
This thing was designed to be untraceable.
也许卡片无迹可寻  但这个不一定
Maybe the card was, but this wasn't.
产自美国  亚特文提斯服饰公司出品
Proudly made in the U.S.A. by Advantus Apparel.
等等  要我赞助分局垒球队吗
So, wait, I'm sponsoring the precinct softball team?
是的  只有这样我才能让
Yeah, it was the only way that I could get Advantus Apparel
亚特文提斯服饰公司把客户名单给我们
to share their client list with us.
他们说四年前已把格林布拉特的订单
Now, they said that they shipped the Greenblatt order
送到这里了
to this office four years ago.
这里是什么地方
What is this place?
我不知道
I don't know.
整层楼都没有登记
This whole floor is unlisted.
我想这一定是个秘密实验室
I think it's a secret laboratory
他们把人类当做试验品
where they're injecting human guinea pigs
给他们注射隐形血清
with invisibility serum.
不管是什么
Well, whatever it is,
凶手绝对不希望我们找到
the killer definitely didn't want us to find it.
你们好
Oh, hello, there.
我猜这一定不是格林布拉特保险公司
I'm betting this isn't Greenblatt Insurance.
你好  我是贝克特探长  纽约警局
Hi. I'm detective Beckett, NYPD.
我们想知道威廉·法维克
We were wondering if a William Fairwick
是否是这里的雇员
is an employee here.
让我找人来帮忙
Let me get someone to assist you.
这里到底从事什么业务
What kind of business is this, exactly?
稍等片刻
It'll be just a moment.
我好喜欢这件夹克
I love that jacket.
把手举起来  都把手举起来
Hands! Show me your hands!
已经核实过你的证件了
Your credentials check out.
如果你和卡塞尔先生立即离开这里
If you and Mr. Castle vacate the premises immediately,
我们就不会以擅闯罪向联邦政府提出起诉
we'll refrain from filing Federal trespassing charges.
对不起  我们在调查一起谋杀案
I'm sorry, we're investigating a homicide.
得到答复前  是不会离开的
We're not leaving without answers.
向联邦政府提出起诉
Uh, Federal charges?
这一定是个绝密的政府机构
It's a top-secret government facility.
我说得对  隐形血清
I was right. Invisibility serum.
你刚才说什么
What did you say?
我刚才说我说得对
I said I was right.
收到  夫人
Copy that, ma'am.
你们好  我是伊莲娜·萨科夫博士
Hello. I'm Dr. Elena Sarkov.
你刚才说隐形血清是什么意思
What did you mean by invisibility serum?
-我只是说  -卡塞尔
- I was just saying that -- - Castle.
如果想知道答案
If you want answers,
你必须先回答我们几个问题
you're gonna have to give us some first.
除非你希望整个纽约警局的人来敲你的门
Unless you want the entire NYPD knocking on your front door.
你们想知道什么
What do you want to know?
这里是什么地方  跟法维克有什么关系
What is this place and how is will Fairwick connected to it?
卡塞尔先生说得对
Mr. Castle is correct.
这里是政府机构
This is a government facility.
中情局  还是国土安全部
CIA? Homeland Security.
莫非是国防高级研究计划局
Ah-ah! D.A.R.P.A.?
差不多吧
Something like that.
威尔在这里工作
Will worked here,
他的死对我们来说是莫大的损失
and his death was quite a loss to us.
这么说你知道他被谋杀了
So, you know about his murder.
他在这是做什么的
What did he do here?
他曾是我手下的一名科学家
He was one of my scientists.
量子工程学  我从麻省理工把他招来的
Quantum engineering. I recruited him out of M.I.T.
招募
Recruited?
等等  这么说他并没崩溃
Wait, so then he never had a breakdown.
只是掩人耳目的借口
Cover story to avoid questions.
量子工程学  国防高级研究计划局
Quantum engineering? D.A.R.P.A.?
你们的确在研究隐形
You are researching invisibility.
不  卡塞尔先生  隐形纯属科幻
No, Mr. Castle. Invisibility is science fiction.
隐身衣才是科学
Cloaking, however, is science.
我已经回答了你们的问题  现在该我问了
I have answered your questions. Now answer mine.
你们是怎么发现我们研究的技术的
How did you find out about our technology?
在调查过程中
During our investigation,
我们曾遇到一个看不见的人
we encountered an unseen person...
隐形人
Invisible person.
出现在威尔的家里
...at Will's apartment.
我们认为不管幕后真凶是谁
We believe this whoever was behind his murder,
鉴于你们所研究的项目
and given the research that you're doing here,
我们认为凶手和这间机构有关
we believe the killer is connected to this facility.
这不可能
That's impossible.
-我们清楚看见了什么  -或没看见什么
- We know what we saw. - Or didn't see.
不  我说不可能
No, it's impossible
是因为我们的技术还未起效
because we haven't gotten our technology to work.
不过我知道是谁干的
But I think I know who did.
中国人吗
The Chinese?
他们一直在研究这项技术
They've been pursuing the same technology.
我们听说他们接近了突破点
We heard they were close to a breakthrough.
你为什么怀疑他们
Why would you suspect them?
因为几天前
Because a few days ago,
我们遭受了严重的网络攻击
we suffered a crippling cyber attack.
所有的数据都被清除了
All of our data was wiped out.
我们的团队追踪病毒
Our team managed to trace the virus
到上海的一个中转站
to a relay station in Shanghai.
是件隐形衣
It's a suit.
怎么使它隐形
How does it turn invisible?
通过异介质使光线产生折射
By bending light waves over meta materials.
你们的玩具太酷了
You guys have the coolest toys.
我就是用这个把威尔吸引到这里来
It's what I promised Will to lure him here.
有机会和先进的政府科技近距离接触
The opportunity to play - with advanced government tech.
当然了  作为一个无政府主义者
Of course, as an anarchist,
他把这笑称为和魔鬼结下的契约
he joked it was his deal with the devil.
如果你是对的  中国人也有这样一件衣服
If you're right and the Chinese do have a working suit,
他们为什么攻击威尔呢
why would they target Will?
21世纪  技术就是军备比拼
Technology is the arms race of the 21st century.
威尔是我们研究的核心人物
And Will was the key to our research.
他的死  令我们的研究倒退了好几年
His death... sets us back years.
-我失陪一下  -好的
- Excuse me for just one moment. - Yeah.
卡塞尔
Castle.
如果这事幕后主使是中国人
If the Chinese are behind this,
他们为什么要阻止我们拿走威尔的门卡
why would they try to stop us from taking Will's key card,
塔尔梅奇和他们又有什么关系
And what do they have to do with Talmadge?
我觉得不是中国人
I don't think it's the Chinese.
为什么
Why not?
看到这里的符号了吗  这里
Do you see that symbol there that -- there.
在病毒中不断重复那个  这不是中国字
It keeps repeating in the virus -- the one that isn't Chinese.
那是《大地远征》东山妖精的标志
It's a symbol of the east mountain goblins from "Terra Quest."
威尔的邻居
Will's neighbor.
亨利·怀特
Henry Wright.
警员去了亨利·怀特的公寓
Unis went - to Henry Wright's apartment,
全空了  衣柜和抽屉干干净净
Found it cleaned out -- closet and dresser emptied.
那家伙跑了
Dude's gone.
调查他有什么结果
What have we found on him?
他是个很有水平的黑客
Well, he's a serious hacker.
15岁时  黑进了市电力公司
At 15, he cracked the city's power grid.
他到20来岁  才接受现身说法教育
Didn't get scared straight until he was in his 20s.
现在是网络管理
Now he's a sneaker,
为财富500强企业测试防火墙
testing cyber defenses for fortune 500 companies.
就是说他拥有网络攻击
Which means he had the skills necessary
萨科夫博士实验室的技能
to launch a cyber attack against Dr. Sarkov's lab.
他和这案子还有一个联系
And, uh, he had another connection to this case.
亨利在加州理工曾经与  稍等
Henry attended Caltech with -- wait for it --
被袭击受害人汤姆·塔尔梅奇是同学
Assault victim Tom Talmadge.
他们曾是室友
They were roommates.
这是亨利起诉塔尔梅奇的案子
This is the lawsuit that Henry filed against Talmadge,
指控他盗取了代码
accusing him of stealing the code
后来开发出Hytch
that he used to build Hytch.
被法院驳回了
The court dismissed the case.
令亨利没能成为亿万富翁
Costing Henry billions.
萨科夫说她的实验室没有破解隐形技术
Sarkov said her lab hadn't cracked the cloaking technology,
但如果威尔在邻居亨利的帮忙下破解了呢
but what if Will did with a little help from his neighbor, Henry?
有了起效的隐形衣
And with a functioning suit,
亨利可以在威尔的帮助下
Henry could've enlisted Will's help
向塔尔梅奇报复
to get revenge against Talmadge.
但亨利仍需帮助才能破解塔尔梅奇的家庭安保系统
But Henry still needed help defeating Talmadge's home security.
隐形并不能破解热能或压力系统
Invisibility doesn't defeat thermal or pressure systems.
所以亨利穿着隐形衣
So, they hustled Jiggy
他们联手坑了吉格
while Henry was wearing that invisibility suit.
是亨利移动了球桌上的白球
Henry is the one that was moving the cue ball around the table.
也许当亨利意识到隐形衣的作用后
And perhaps once Henry realized the power of the suit,
他就盯上了威尔
he set his sights on Will,
确保隐形衣永远不会被夺走
Making sure that power would never be taken away.
好吧  怎么找这小子
Okay, how do we find this kid?
没办法  这家伙是顶级黑客
We don't. The guy's a high-level hacker.
他有了新的身份  现在应该已经出国了
He's got a new I.D. and he's out of the country by now.
他会利用自己的技能  像国王一样生活
He'll trade on his skills and live like a king.
事实上  他已经像国王一样生活着
Actually, he's already living like a king,
这会助我们找到他
and that's how we're gonna find him.
欢迎来到《大地远征》  冒险在等着你
Welcome to "Terra Quest." Adventure awaits.
好了
All right.
东山妖精大军
East mountain goblin army is attacking
从奥尔峰基地开始进攻
from the base of mt. Orr,
就是说他们的国王会带领他们进入战斗
which means their king will be leading them into battle.
他在那里
There he is.
那是亨利
That's Henry.
他在哪里弄了一把青龙剑
Where did he get a falchion sword?
那玩意要90以上的征服分呢
That's like plus-90 conquest points.
可以锁定头像吗
Can you get a lock on that avatar
看能否追踪到亨利在哪里登陆的
and see if you can trace the location where Henry logged in?
我想可以
I think so.
我会加入战斗
And I will join the battle...
拖住他
...And slow him down.
我还以为地下游戏窝点只是传说呢
I thought underground gaming dens were just legend.
我还以为隐形人也不是真的呢
Yeah, well, I thought - the invisible man wasn't real.
他在那里
There he is.
亨利
Henry!
站住  站住
Stop! Stop!
拦住他
Stop him!
站住
Stop!
现在青龙剑在谁手中啊
Who's got the falchion sword now?
我没有杀威尔  他是我的朋友
I didn't murder Will. He was my friend.
那你为什么要跑  亨利
Then why did you run, Henry?
我们知道你找过汤姆·塔尔梅奇麻烦
Look, we know that you went after Tom Talmadge.
你策划了一起网络攻击
You were behind a cyber attack
搞垮了政府实验室
that brought down a government lab,
然后你清空你的公寓消失了
And then you cleaned out your apartment and you disappeared.
因为我害怕他们接下来会找我
Because I was afraid that they would come after me next.
谁
Who?
杀掉威尔的人
The same people that killed Will.
如果他们发现我知道...
All right, if they found out that I knew...
你知道什么
That you knew what?
你帮了他对吗
You helped him, didn't you?
你帮他造了隐形衣
You helped him build a working suit.
威尔带着超前的想法来找我
Will came to me with an out-there idea.
他要将自然伪装运用到
He wanted to adopt nature's camouflage
结构材料中
to meta materials.
但他的实验室
But there wasn't anybody in his lab
没人有我这种编码技术  因为我不可能
that had my program skills, and since there was no way
通过安全审查
I was gonna get security clearance,
我们只能偷偷地进行
we worked on the down low.
作为交换  你可以用他的隐形衣
And in exchange, you got to use his suit
向塔尔梅奇报复  对吗
to exact your revenge against Talmadge, right?
本不该发生的
That wasn't supposed to happen.
我只是在找证据
I was just looking for proof
证明汤姆偷了我开发Hytch的理念
that Tom stole my idea for Hytch.
但他被打断的肋骨可没有证实你的话
Yeah, well, - his broken ribs say otherwise.
我找不到需要的证据
I couldn't find what I needed.
然后汤姆提前回到家
And then Tom came home early.
我只是想捉弄他一下
I-I just wanted to mess with him.
但我失控了
But I snapped.
威尔听到挣扎声  进来拉开了我
Will heard the struggle, he came in, and he pulled me off.
威尔制止你  你生气了
You got angry with Will for stopping you.
所以你决定用他的隐形衣来干掉他
So, you decided to use his suit to kill him instead, right?
不
No!
我们都意识到我变成了佛罗多
We both realized that I had become Frodo,
那件隐形衣就是统治一切的魔戒
and the suit was the one ring to rule them all!
威尔知道任谁拥有都会得到过大的权力
Will knew it was too much power for anyone to have,
尤其是政府
especially the government.
所以威尔成了奥本海默[曼哈顿计划领导者之一]
So, that was Will's Oppenheimer moment.
隐形衣变成了原子弹
The suit became the atomic bomb.
隐形衣需要被销毁
All right, - it needed to be destroyed.
投进魔域之火
Cast into the fires of mordor.
我们黑进实验室是为了使他们无法重建该技术
We sabotaged the lab so that they couldn't rebuild the tech,
至少不是马上重建
at least not right away.
没了威尔从头足类动物那
And without the quantum cellular equations
导出的量子细胞方程式
Will derived from cephalopods,
他们可能永远也重建不了
they may never be able to.
头足类动物  鱿鱼吗
Cephalopods? Like squids?
事实上  威尔
Actually, um, Will,
的方程式是通过墨鱼得出的
he based his equations off of the cuttlefish.
墨鱼是大自然公认的
The cuttlefish is known
伪装之王
as nature's king of camouflage.
听这段
And listen to this.
墨鱼的乳突有着独特的能力
"The papillae of the cuttlefish are unique in their ability
通过迅速极化反射光波
"to rapidly polarize reflected light waves
改变其表皮颜色
and change the creature's skin color."
这才是威尔联系多娜的原因
That's why will got back in touch with donna.
他不是还惦念着她  他想要她的研究
He didn't want her. He wanted her research.
卡塞尔  看威尔的通讯记录
Castle, look at Will's phone records.
连续多周  他俩之间
For weeks, there were phone calls
有着多次的相互通话
going back and forth between the two of them,
在他死前三天
and then three days before his death,
就是在他让隐形衣起效之时
right when he got that suit to function,
就只有她打给他的电话了
there were only incoming calls from her.
威尔不接电话了
Will wasn't answering.
谋杀案之后  她就不打电话了
And right after will was murdered, she stops calling,
就好像她已经知道他死了似的
almost as if she knew he was dead.
伙计们  我给大学打了电话
Hey, guys. I called the university.
猜猜谁在威尔被谋杀那晚取消了自己的课
Guess who canceled their class the night will was killed.
怎么回事
What's going on here?
这是私人办公室
This is a private office.
隶属于这所大学
Which belongs to the university.
校长给了我们搜查的允许
The dean gave us permission to search it
作为我们调查的一部分
as a part of our investigation.
等等  你认为我跟威尔的死有关
Wait. You think I had something to do with Will's death?
多娜  他被杀那晚你错过了自己的课
Donna, you missed your class the night that he was killed.
你在哪
Where were you?
感冒在家休息
At home with a cold.
我不会伤害威尔的  我爱他
I never would've hurt Wwill. I loved him.
你爱他  他却背叛了你
You loved him, but then he betrayed you.
他的背叛一定令你很愤怒
That must have made you angry to find out
发现他不过是在利用你得到研究成果
that he was just using you for your research.
那不是真的
That's not true.
那是他第二次抛弃你
That was the second time that he left you,
他令你蒙羞  你无法接受这一切
and you couldn't live with the embarrassment.
胡说  这太扯了
This is ridiculous.
我不会站在这
I'm not gonna stand here
任由你们指责我杀害了我的男友
and let you accuse me of killing my boyfriend.
多娜  是你穿着隐形衣在公寓与我们搏斗
Donna, that was you in the suit in the apartment with us.
你用同一件隐形衣杀了威尔
That's the same suit that you used to kill Will.
你发现了他的研究
You found out about his project,
在他毁掉它之前
and before he could destroy it,
你用他自己的发明解决了他
you used his own creation against him.
什么隐形衣  你在说什么
What suit? What are you talking about?
你穿着那件去抢威尔的门卡
The suit you wore when you went after Will's key card
却最终拿走了我的信用卡
and you got my credit card instead.
刚刚在你抽屉末端底部找到的
Just found it buried in the back of your drawer.
随便感谢你  我忘记挂失了
Thank you for that, by the way. I forgot to cancel this.
要是挂失  解挂很麻烦的
That can be such a pain.
我应该做什么  放过他吗
What was I supposed to do, let him get away with it?
他不再打来电话  不再发短信
He stopped calling, stopped texting.
他利用了我
He used me!
还竟敢假装我不存在
And then pretended like I didn't exist.
他希望我从他的生活中消失
He wanted me to just disappear from his life.
我的确消失了
So I did.
我让他措手不及
And he never saw me coming.
多娜·布鲁克斯  你因谋杀
Donna Brooks, you're under arrest --
-去追  -好
- You go. - Okay. Okay.
我来放下这个
Okay, I'll get this.
她的背包和衣服
Her backpack and clothes.
她穿上了隐形衣
She's wearing the suit.
卡塞尔  抵住门
Castle, block the door.
好
Right.
这次不会让她溜走了
She is not slipping past this time.
多娜  你跑不掉的
Donna, there's nowhere to go.
这下你完蛋了
Yeah, gotcha now!
我好想念咱俩心有灵犀啊
I so missed these mind melds.
两点钟方向
2 o'clock!
她在那
She's right there.
贝克特  如果你能隐形会做什么
Beckett, what would you do if you were invisible?
我会在没有完成案件报告的情况下开溜
I'd walk out of here without having to file this report.
无聊
Boring.
你呢  卡塞尔
How about you, Castle?
潜伏在贝克特老爸家  看他对我到底什么印象
Be a fly on the wall, see what Beckett's dad really thinks of me.
这是什么
What's this?
是时候穿上正经的制服了
"Time you had a proper uniform.
爱你的  哈维
Love, Javi."
爱心满满的礼物  兄弟
It's from the heart, bro.
好吧
Okay.
太大了
Too big?
愿意帮我试穿吗
Want to help me try it on?
他们告诉我这是新的
They told me it was new.
人家需要你的帮助吗  蓝色是我最爱颜色
I could really use your help. What? Blue is my color.
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
没必要难为情
You don't have to be embarrassed.
我们会把它带走保管  卡塞尔先生
We'll be taking custody of that, mr. Castle.
威尔而觉得这玩意对一个人来说
You know, Will thought this was too much power
给予的权力过大
for any one person to have,
发生这么多事
and after everything that's happened,
我同意他的看法
I think I agree.
这种科学有点像与恶魔的协定
This kind of science is a bit of a deal with the devil.
小心不要出卖自己的灵魂
Be careful not to lose your soul.
老妈今晚出去嗨了
Mother is out for the evening.
阿丽克西斯在图书馆通宵
Alexis is pulling - an all-nighter at the library.
这么说  我们终于独处了
So, we're actually, truly really alone?
这玩意今早送来的
This came in this morning.
转换成热影像
Switching to thermal.
扫描房间
Scanning the room.
安全
The room is clear,
除了我面前这个很火辣的物体
All except for the very hot object before me.
好了
Okay.
稍等片刻  我换件特别的  好吗
Give me a minute and let me slip into something special, okay?
好的
Right.
我在情人节给你买了件特别的
'cause there's something special i got you for valentine's day.
我赞同那件
I approve.
这件更赞
It's even better.
隐形的
It's invisible.